nowpublic.net 2012-12-04

# Privacy Policy | Community | Newsroom | NowPublic

**Scope of This Privacy Policy**

Thank you for visiting NowPublic.com. The NowPublic.com website (the “Site”) is operated by Clarity Digital Group LLC ("CDG") and its subsidiary Now Public Technologies, Inc. (“NowPublic”). Your privacy on the Internet is extremely important to us, and we want to make your experience on our Site satisfying and safe. This Privacy Policy applies to information about you collected through our Site. This Privacy Policy is part of and incorporated into the [**Terms of Use**](http://www.nowpublic.com/help/terms_and_conditions) for our Site.

**Types of Information**

We collect two types of information through our Site. “ **PII** ” means “personally identifiable information,” which is information that identifies you personally, either alone or in combination with other information available to us (including without limitation your name, address, email address, telephone number, age, background, or other personal information). **Non-PII** ” means “non-personally identifiable information” or information that alone does not identify you (however, in some circumstances Non-PII may be combined with PII in order to identify a specific individual).

**Your Consent to This Privacy Policy**

By using our Site, you are agreeing to the collection, use, and disclosure of your PII and Non-PII as described in this Privacy Policy. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices related to the Site, please email us at [legal@nowpublic.com.](mailto:legal@nowpublic.com)

**Information We Gather and Track**

In order to access or use certain services and capabilities on our Site or to participate in certain programs, you may be required to voluntarily submit certain PII through our Site. The use of these services or capabilities or participation in these programs is purely optional, so you are not required to submit any PII through our Site if you do not wish to do so. For example, you may wish to provide PII in connection with registering on our Site; creating a profile on our Site; sharing content from our Site; participation in commenting features, surveys, contests, sweepstakes, referral programs or other promotions; or submitting feedback to us. This information may include your name, address, email address, and other information you voluntarily provide to us, as well as information we may track regarding the content you have viewed on our Site. 

We also collect Non-PII through our Site. The Non-PII collected does not by itself identify you personally. However, if you have registered on the Site, it may be possible for us to link certain Non-PII to information that identifies you personally. Non-PII collected through our Site may include: information sent to us automatically by your web browser such as your IP address, the address of the web page you were visiting when you accessed our Site, information on your operating system (e.g., Microsoft Windows or Mac OS), the browser you are using (e.g., Firefox, Internet Explorer, Safari); the date and time of your visit; user traffic patterns and content accessed throughout our Site; and search terms you may enter in our Search function. This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers' needs and to help our advertisers and sponsors better understand our audience.

**How Information is Gathered**

In order to improve your experience when using our Site, we, our third party service providers, or advertisers may place a text file called a "cookie" in the browser files of your computer, which stores your preferences and may be used to help personalize your experience. We, our third party service providers, or advertisers may also use “web beacons,” “pixel tags” or similar technologies, which are small pieces of code placed on a web page to monitor behavior and collect certain data regarding the actions of our users online. These cookies and other technologies may be used to track user traffic patterns, to enhance your experience when using our Site, to persist information through your session, to personalize the Site for you based on your preferences and selections, to target advertising or content to you as described further below, and to collect Non-PII about you and your visit to our Site for other marketing and business purposes. You can adjust your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies and similar technologies through your browser. Disabling cookies may result in a less complete experience while using the Site.

**Third Party Advertising; Targeting of Ads and Content**

We may use third party companies to serve ads on our Site, to provide us with data collection, ad response measurement, ad or content targeting, and other marketing or related services. We have granted permission to these companies and certain advertisers or customers of these companies to use cookies, web beacons, pixel tags or similar technologies in order to collect Non-PII about our users (subject to their own privacy guidelines) for purposes of generating advertisements and other content targeted to your interests, and for other data collection, response measurement, marketing and related business purposes. The privacy policy of one of our ad-serving partners, DoubleClick, may be accessed at this link: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html#utm_source=dfp_footer&utm_medium=et&utm_campaign=dfp) Our service providers are subject to change from time to time.

The Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”), a cooperative group of ad serving providers that has developed a set of privacy principles to which its members adhere, provides a website offering more information about behavioral advertising practices and your choices about not having certain Non-PII used by certain companies in order to target advertisements to you, as well as information about NAI and third party ad servers in general. You may visit the NAI site and opt out of certain behavioral advertising practices at [www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp)

**Use of Information**

CDG, its related entities, or certain carefully selected third parties with whom we have business relationships may use PII or Non-PII collected on our Site:

  * To enhance or personalize your experience using our Site; 

  * To inform you of offers or new features that we believe may be of interest to you;

  * To provide information or services you have requested;

  * To process or maintain your registration on the Site or content contributor applications; 

  * To process orders and facilitate advertisements or sponsorships on our Site;

  * In connection with various programs, promotions or contests in which you participate;

  * For targeting of advertising or content, or other advertising or marketing purposes;

  * To study the use and popularity of various areas of our Site and to improve our Site;

  * To analyze where we are getting our audience;

  * For other purposes related to the business of CDG and its related entities, and for any other purpose described in this Privacy Policy or as we may disclose to you or to which you consent from time to time.

We may create aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers, sponsors and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their interests. We will not intentionally collect (nor intentionally provide to an advertiser or sponsor) information that a personally-identified user clicked on any particular ad. However, by clicking on, otherwise interacting with or viewing an ad, you are consenting to the possibility that the advertiser will make the assumption that you meet the targeting criteria used to display the ad, and this may lead to similar ads being targeted to you on our Site and potentially on other Sites.

**Sharing of Information**

We may share your PII with: (i) our current or future affiliates, subsidiaries, parent company, or other related entities (" **CDG Entities** "); (ii) companies and organizations that perform services on our behalf (such as data storage, web hosting, or other services); and (iii) carefully selected third parties for purposes relating to content creation or distribution deals, selected promotions of CDG or our related entities, or third party promotions we believe would be of interest to you, marketing activities, ad targeting as described above, or other purposes relevant to the business of NowPublic and/or CDG.

We may also disclose the PII and Non-PII we collect through our Site when we, in good faith, believe disclosure is appropriate to comply with the law or legal process (including a court order or subpoena); to prevent or investigate a possible crime; to enforce our Site’s [Terms of Use](http://www.nowpublic.com/help/terms_and_conditions) or other agreements that you have entered into with NowPublic or other CDG Entities or that govern your use of our Site; to protect the rights, property or safety of our business, our users or others; or to protect your vital interests.

We may share analyses of our server logs, including details regarding Site usage and general information about our audience, with current or potential advertisers or business partners. Such disclosures will refer only to general, aggregate usage data from these analyses - never specific identifying information.

Information submitted to our Site will become part of our normal business records. Your PII may be transferred to another company that acquires the stock or assets of NowPublic and/or CDG, for example, as the result of a sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or liquidation. If such a transfer occurs, the acquiring company's use of your PII will still be subject to this Privacy Policy, and any privacy choices you selected on our Site.

Please be aware that although we may request your consent for some disclosures described in this section, by using our Site you are deemed to have consented to the collection, sharing, disclosure, processing, transfer, and other uses of your information collected through our Site in the manner described in this Privacy Policy, and we will not be required to obtain your consent for any collection, sharing, disclosure, processing, transfer, and other uses described in this Privacy Policy. 

**User Profiles; Comments; and Other PII Posted by You**

If you choose to participate as a content contributor on our Site, you choose to register and create a profile as a user of our Site, or you choose to post comments on our Site, please be aware that your profile (if applicable) and any information you post on our Site (within your profile, comments, or otherwise), including without limitation your name, photo, and any PII you provide in your public profile, as well as certain information regarding your actions on our Site, may automatically be visible to the general public, and will potentially remain on the Site indefinitely.

To the extent you have posted PII in your public user profile, in articles or comments on the Site, or otherwise in a publicly displayed manner on our Site, that information is available to the general public and can be used in connection with distribution and promotion of such content to third parties, for news reporting related to the article or comment in which the PII is located on our Site, or for other similar purposes, due to the fact that the information became public when you posted it on our Site.

**Third Party Websites**

Third party websites, including our partners, advertisers, related entities, and other content providers featured on our Site or accessible through links on our Site, may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. You may encounter these third party sites through links in content on our Site, advertisements, features, contests, sweepstakes or other promotions featured on or accessible via links from our Site. We do not have any control over these third parties’ use of the information you may provide to them. We are not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties and we are not liable to you for any claims that may arise from your interaction with those third parties or their sites. You should exercise caution and check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing PII or another party’s information on a feature or page operated by a third party.

**International Users – Transfer of Information**

CDG is headquartered in the United States, and you understand that any PII collected on the Site is collected and transferred to CDG in the United States and may be shared with CDG Entities in Canada or elsewhere. You hereby consent to the transfer to and processing of any PII by CDG and any CDG-related Entities, or any of the other parties listed in the preceding paragraph "Sharing of Information," whether located in the United States or any other countries, for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, or for any other specific purposes to which you consent. If you are located in a country other than the United States, you should note that, at present, the laws of the United States and certain other countries have not been approved by the European Commission or privacy authorities in certain other countries as providing "adequate protection" for personal information within the meaning of the EU Data Protection Directive or applicable laws of other countries. Please know, however, that no matter where your personal information is collected, used, transferred or stored, if it was collected through the Site, it will be protected by the terms of this Privacy Policy. YOU HEREBY CONSENT TO THE USE AND PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA IN THE UNITED STATES OR IN ANY OTHER COUNTRY IN THE MANNER SET FORTH HEREIN. 

**Children's Privacy**

Consistent with the Federal Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request PII from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent. The Site is not directed at nor targeted to children under the age of 13 and we do not use the Site to knowingly solicit PII from or market to children under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 13, do not provide us with any PII. If we learn that someone under 13 has provided PII to the Site, we will use reasonable efforts to remove such information from our databases.

**How We Protect Information**

We operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection systems. Our security and privacy policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary. Only authorized individuals have access to the PII provided by our Site’s users.

**Accessing and Modifying Personal Information and Preferences**

We respect your right to make choices about the ways we collect, use and disclose your PII. If you have registered on our Site you may update or modify your information or change your preferences at any time by logging in to the applicable section of our Site using your user name and password, and updating your user profile. If you have not registered on our Site or you are having trouble updating your profile and you wish to review or modify PII we may have collected about you, please email us at [legal@nowpublic.com](mailto:legal@nowpublic.com). You may also opt-out of receiving communications from us by adjusting your subscriptions’ settings under the “Preferences” section of your account, or by emailing us at legal@nowpublic.com. Nonetheless, please be aware that certain activity on the website may generate an email from NowPublic.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, our privacy practices in connection with this Site, or our collection, sharing, disclosure, processing, transfer, and other uses of your personal information in connection with this Site, please contact us follows:

Privacy Officer

c/o Clarity Digital Group LLC

555 17th Street, Suite 700

Denver, CO 80202

U.S.A.

By email: legal@nowpublic.com

**This Privacy Policy May Change**

We reserve the right to update or modify this Privacy Policy, at any time and without prior notice, by posting the revised version of this Privacy Policy on the Site. Your use of the Site following any such change constitutes your agreement that all information collected from or about you through the Site after the revised Privacy Policy is posted will be subject to the terms of the revised Privacy Policy. You may access the current version of this Privacy Policy at any time by clicking on the link marked "Privacy Policy" at the bottom of each page of our Site.

**This Privacy Policy is effective as of September 27, 2011.**
